<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-08-01T06:39:07+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Quoc Dung Van</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Preparing to Graduate from UVIC MADS Program</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/blog/2025/prepare-tp-graduate/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Preparing to Graduate from UVIC MADS Program"/><published>2025-07-31T16:40:16+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-31T16:40:16+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/blog/2025/prepare-tp-graduate</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/blog/2025/prepare-tp-graduate/"><![CDATA[<p>As I approach the end of my final semester in the Master of Applied Data Science (MADS) program at the University of Victoria, I find myself reflecting on an incredible journey of learning and growth. This program has transformed not just my technical skills, but my entire approach to problem-solving and data-driven thinking.</p> <h4 id="what-ive-learned">What I’ve Learned</h4> <p>The MADS program has equipped me with a comprehensive toolkit for data analytics:</p> <ul> <li><strong>Statistical Analysis &amp; Machine Learning</strong>: From foundational statistics to advanced ML algorithms</li> <li><strong>Data Visualization</strong>: Creating compelling narratives through data storytelling</li> <li><strong>Big Data Technologies</strong>: Working with distributed systems and cloud platforms</li> <li><strong>Programming</strong>: Proficiency in Python, R, SQL, and various data science frameworks</li> <li><strong>Business Intelligence</strong>: Translating data insights into actionable business strategies</li> <li><strong>Ethics in Data Science</strong>: Understanding the responsibility that comes with data handling</li> </ul> <h4 id="the-journey">The Journey</h4> <p>This final semester has been particularly rewarding. The capstone project allowed me to apply everything I’ve learned to a real-world problem, demonstrating the practical value of data science in industry contexts. The collaborative nature of the program taught me how to work effectively in cross-functional teams, a skill that’s invaluable in today’s data-driven workplace.</p> <h4 id="ready-for-industry">Ready for Industry</h4> <p>After months of intensive coursework, projects, and hands-on experience, I feel confident and prepared to enter the data analytics industry. The program hasn’t just taught me technical skills—it’s taught me how to think critically about data, ask the right questions, and communicate findings effectively to both technical and non-technical stakeholders.</p> <blockquote> <p>“Data is not just numbers; it’s the foundation for informed decision-making and innovation.”</p> </blockquote> <p>I’m excited about the opportunities ahead and grateful for the solid foundation that UVIC’s MADS program has provided. The knowledge and skills I’ve gained here will serve as the launching pad for a successful career in data analytics.</p> <h4 id="looking-forward">Looking Forward</h4> <p>As I prepare to graduate, I’m eager to apply my knowledge in real-world scenarios, contribute to meaningful projects, and continue learning in this rapidly evolving field. The data analytics industry is full of possibilities, and I’m ready to make my mark.</p> <p>Thank you to all the professors, classmates, and industry professionals who made this journey possible. Here’s to the next chapter!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="personal-journey"/><category term="graduation"/><category term="data-analytics"/><category term="MADS"/><category term="UVIC"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reflecting on my final semester and the journey through data analytics]]></summary></entry></feed>